AKASH GIRI

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT 437-460 - 1743 akashgiri2055@gmail.com akash1998.vercel.app linkedin.com/in/akashgiri1998 github.com/akashgiri1998 Canada SKILLS Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, Python, PHP, C#, C++ Technologies, Tools and Database: MERN(MongoDB, Express, React and Node), Wordpress, React Native, nextjs, Bootstrap, GraphQL, Git, JIRA, postgreSQL, etc.

EDUCATION

Ontario College Graduate Certificate On **Computer Software and Database** Development

Loyalist College

Jan 2023 - Aug 2024

Courses: Emerging Dev Technologies, Full Stack Software Development, Database Management, Web Security

Bachelor's in Computer Engineering Kathmandu University

Sep 2016 - Nov 2020 Courses: Data Structure and Algorithms(DSA), System Analysis and Design, Human Computer Interaction(HCI), Software Engineering, Database Management System, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Graphics

LA	N	G	U	Α	G	Ε	S
----	---	---	---	---	---	---	---

English	
Nepali	
Hindi	

PROFILE

Software Developer with 3+ years of professional experience in the FrontEnd and Mobile Application Development. Exploring and growing in the software development field every month by 5% through practice, research and interest to learn about the market requirement according to the present context. My expertise extends to developing elegant and responsive UIs, implementing complex functionalities, and optimizing performance to meet and exceed client expectations. Committed to delivering high-quality solutions that align with industry best practices

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Nurse For Care. Toronto. Canada

April 2024 - August 2024

- . Updates on the Nurse For Care, Centennial Health Care, and Aryal Recruitment websites which is a home care service provider platform.
- Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Wordpress, Hostinger, GoDaddy, etc.

Software Developer

Touchware IT Service Pvt. Ltd. (Kotuko), Italy

June 2022 - Mar 2024

- Implemented Storybook to streamline the development and testing of UI components, reducing development time by 25% as measured by code review feedback and post-release bug reports.
- Technologies Used: React Native, Redux, Storybook, Rest API's, Slack, Jira, Git,

React / React Native Developer

Softhover, United States

Nov 2020 - May 2022

- Created a ReactJS-based admin interface for the website and transitioned an existing React web app of TripLocator to React Native, meeting project requirements and enhancing the platform's administrative capabilities.
- Technologies Used: React, React Native, API's, Git, Redux, Context API, nextis, GraphQL, npm/ yarn,node, etc.

Projects

1. Sahooji

• Sahooji is a platform created with the motive of providing services to the customers with ease which includes plumbing, hair salons, electricity issues and so on. This is the mobile application created using React Native, Typescript, GraphQL, postgreSQL, etc.

2. KU Canteen Management System

• This is a semester project of university which was created to make it easy for every novice user to use this Canteen System of our university following the principles of Human Computer Interaction. Python programming language was used to develop this application.

Participations/Certifications

- Designer of IT Express Magazine
- 10 Days Conference of Second Nepal Winter School in Artificial Intelligence(AI) -> Selected among 10,000 applicants to participate for this conference where the top instructor and the participants from different countries have been involved
- · React Certification from HackerRank
- Certified Learning AWS(Amazon Web Services) for Developers